The Jungle Book《森林王子》1967
Sync & Encoded by Owen Lee
看电影学英语 看美剧学英语
智能手机、IPAD、MP4学英语，请观注：
=-www.en580.com-=『英语我帮您』
许多奇异的传说是讲述印度这片丛林的
Many strange legends are told Of these jungles of India...
没有一个传说能比名叫毛戈力的小男孩的传说更奇异
but none so strange as the story of a small boy named Mowgli.
这个传说开始于一种打破丛林寂静的奇怪的声音
It all began when the silence Of the jungle was broken by an unfamiliar sound.
这种声音在这片丛林从来没听见过
It was a sound like one never heard before in this part of the jungle.
一个婴儿的声音
It was a man cub!
如果知道后来那些事儿有多麻烦
Had I known how deeply I was to be involved...
我本该听从最初的直觉--走开
I would've obeyed my first impulse and walked away.
这个婴孩该吃点食物了，要快
This man cub would have to have nourishment, and soon.
但最近的村子也要走好多天...
It was many days travel to the nearest man village...
没妈妈的照顾，他很快会死
and without a mother's care, he would soon perish.
我想到了
Then it occurred to me.
我认识的一家狼刚幸运地产下一窝小崽
A family of wolves I knew had been blessed with a litter of cubs.
我知道, 由于母性的本能,母亲毫无问题，不过...
Oh, I knew there'd be no problem with the mother thanks to the maternal instinct, but...
对父亲——罗摩，我没把握
I wasn't so sure about Rama, the father.
雨季来来往往了十次
Ten times the rains had come and gone.
我经常顺便去看看人兽过得怎样了
And I often stopped by to see how Mowgli the man cub was getting along.
他是所有一群狼崽中的幸运儿
He was a favorite of all the young wolf cubs of the pack.
没有哪个人兽像他那样快乐
No man cub was ever happier.
然而，我知道有一天
And yet, I knew that someday...
他将不得不回到人群中去
he would have to go back to his own kind.
一天夜晚，狼群中的年长者在议事
Then one night, the wolf pack elders met at council rock...
由于契尔可汗——一只老虎
because Shere Khan the tiger...
已返回这片丛林
had returned to their part of the jungle.
这次会议将改变人兽的一生
This meeting was to change the man cub's entire future.
契尔可汗肯定会杀了小男孩和那些保护他的人
Shere Khan will surely kill the boy and all who try to protect him.
现在，大家都同意要采取的措施吗？
Now, are we all in agreement as to what must be done?
现在我很不情愿地告诉男孩的父亲
Now it is my unpleasant duty to tell the boy's father.
罗摩，请到这边来
Rama. Uh, come over here, please.
好，什么事，阿卡拉?  - 会议已一致通过
Yes, Akela?  - The council has reached its decision.
人兽不能再和狼群呆在一起了
The man cub can no longer stay with the pack.
他必须马上离开  - 离开？
He must leave at once  - Leave?
很抱歉，罗摩， 没其他办法了
I'm sorry, Rama. There is no other way.
但——这个人兽是就象我自己的儿子
But-- But the man cub is -- Well, he's like my own son.
他当然有资格得到狼群的保护
Surely he's entitled to the protection of the pack.
但是，罗摩，即使一群狼的力量也比不过那只老虎
But, Rama, even the strength of the pack is no match for the tiger.
但是那个男孩一个人，在丛林会活不下去啊。
But the boy cannot survive alone in the jungle.
阿卡拉，也许我有办法
Akela. Perhaps I can be of help.
你，巴吉拉?怎么办？
You, Bagheera? How?
我知道一个人类村庄，在那他会安全的
I know of a man village where he'll be safe.
毛戈力和我一起在丛林中走过不少路了，我想他会跟我走的
Mowgli and I have taken many walks into the jungle together, so I'm sure he'll go with me.
就这样。没时间浪费了。祝你好运
So be it. Now there's no time to lose. Good luck.
巴吉拉
Bagheera.
我有点困了，我们要不要回家？
I'm getting a little sleepy. Shouldn't we start back home?
毛戈力，这次我们不回去了
Mowgli, this time we're not going back.
我要带你去一个人类的村庄 - 为什么？
I'm taking you to a man village. - But why?
因为契尔可汗已回到这片丛林
Because Shere Khan has returned to this part of the jungle.
他发誓要杀了你
And he has sworn to kill you.
杀我？他为什么要这样？
Kill me? But why would he wanna do that?
他恨人类
He hates man.
契尔可汗不让你长大成人的
And Shere Khan is not going to allow you to grow up to become a man--
长成为一个拿枪的猎人
just another hunter with a gun.
哦，我们向他解释说我们永远不会那样做的
Aw, we'll just explain to him that I'd never do a thing like that.
废话。没人可以向契尔可汗解释的
Nonsense. No one explains anything to Shere Khan.
也许如此。但我不怕
Well, maybe so. But I'm not afraid.
此外，我--  - 够了，够了
And besides, I--  - Now that's enough.
我们今晚在这过夜。明早一切都会更好的
We'll spend the night here. Things will look better in the morning.
人兽？  人兽！
Man cub? Man cub!
来吧，爬上这棵树。上去时小心些
Now come on, up this tree. Be safer up there.
我不想回到人类村庄
I don't wanna go back to the man village.
继续，向上
Go on. Up you go.
到上面的树枝上吗？ - 对。
That limb way up there? - That's right.
你爬树就这样爬吗？
Is that all the better you can climb?
我-- 噢--这树太大了。
I-- Oh-- It's too big around.
而且，我又没有爪子
And besides, I don't have any claws.
现在睡一觉
Now, get some sleep.
明天我们还得走很多路
We've got a long journey ahead of us tomorrow.
我-- 我想待在丛林中
I-- I wanna stay in the jungle.
恩？多待一天也不行。
Huh? You wouldn't last one day.
我不怕。我-我自己会小心的
I'm not afraid. I-I can look out for myself.
比方说，我们这儿有什么？
Say now, what have we here?
一个人兽
It's a man cub.
一个美味的人兽
A delicious man cub.
哦，走开，不要烦我。
Oh, go away and leave me alone.
恩，我应该那样做，但我不会那样。
Oh, that's just what I should do, but I'm not.
现在，现在，快睡着吧，人兽
Now, now, please go to sleep, man cub.
是，人兽，请睡觉吧。
Yes, man cub. Please go to sleep.
请睡觉吧
Please go to sleep
睡觉，小人兽
Sleep, little man cub
安安静静地休息
Rest in peace
睡吧，睡吧
Sleep. Sleep.
巴-- 巴-巴吉--吉拉
Ba-- Ba-Bagh-gheera.
哦。-- 你看，再争辩也没有用
Oh, now-- Now look, there's no use arguing any more.
恩，天亮前不要再说话了。
Oh! Now no more talk till morning.
他早晨不会在这里
He won't be here in the morning.
恩? 哦，对，他会的 我-- 喀!
Hmm? Oh, yes, he will. I-- Kaa!
等等，喀!
Hold it, Kaa!
哦! 我的下巴
Oh! My sinus.
我的朋友，你刚刚犯了个严重的错误
You have just made a serious mistake, my friend.
一个非常愚蠢的...
A very stupid...
现在，现在，现在，现在，我是-- - 错误
Now, now, now, now, Kaa, I was-- - mistake.
我跟你说话时看着我的眼睛
Look me in the eye when I'm speaking to you.
哦，请吧， 喀 - 两只眼，如果你喜欢
Oh, please, Kaa  - Both eyes, if you please.
现在，你的末日就要来了。
You have just sealed your doom.
看，巴吉拉! 看, 巴吉拉.
Look, Bagheera! Look, Bagheera.
醒醒，巴吉拉.
Wake up, Bagheera.
你们就等着吧，等着我把你们缠起来。
Just you wait till I get you in my coils.
巴吉拉, 他的尾巴打了一个结
Bagheera, he's got a knot in his tail!
他的尾巴打了一个结
"He's got a knot in his tail."
噢，这样让我爬起来要慢很多。
Ooh, this is going to slow down my slither.
所以，你会自己小心的，是吗？
So, you can look out For yourself, can you?
所以，你要待在丛林里，是吗？
So you want to stay in the jungle, do you?
是的，我要待在丛林里。
Yes. I wanna stay in the jungle.
哦! 现在，现在，现在， 说最后一次，去睡觉!
Oh! Now, now, now for the last time, go to sleep!
人兽
Man cub.
嘿，二，三，四
Hup, two, three, four
不松劲 二，三，四
Keep it up Two, three, four
嘿，二，三，四
Hup, two, three, four
不松劲 二，三，四   二，三，四
Keep it up Two, three, four
嘿，二，三，四
Hup, two, three, four
巡逻
A parade.
哦，不! 这是早上的巡逻。
Oh, no! The dawn patrol again.
全队，依次报数
Company, sound off!
哦，我们的巡逻，不是闹着玩的
Oh, the aim of our patrol Is a question rather droll
在平地和山岗，列队操练
For to march and drill Over field and hill
是军事需要
Is a military goal
嘿， 二，三，四
With a hup Two, three, four
整队 二，三，四
Dress it up two, three, four
一列纵队
By the ranks or single file
走遍丛林每寸土地
Over every jungle mile
哦，踏过西部的丛林
Oh, west amp and crush through the underbrush
以军人的姿态
In the military style
你好，你在做什么？
Hello. What are you doing?
嘘! 操练。
Shh! Drilling.
我也参加操练，好吗? - 可以.跟着我做
Can I do it too? - Sure. Just do what I do.
但是不要在队伍里说话，那是违反规定的。
But don't talk in ranks. It's against regulations.
向后转!齐步-走!
To the rear! March!
另一边 转身
The other way. Turn around.
哈，二，三，四
Hup, two, three, four
继续不松劲 二，三，四
Keep it up Two, three, four
向后转！ 豁！
To the rear! Ho!
全队，立定!
Company, halt!
意思是停下来
That means stop.
全队，向左转！
Company, left face!
齐步走，齐步走,齐步走 我的脚可要了我的命
March, march, march. My feet are killing me.
我要被调遣到别的队伍
I'm puttin' in for a transfer to another herd.
请安静!
Silence in the ranks!
打起精神
Dress up that line.
快跑，威尼弗雷德
Pull it in, Winifred.
开始检查！武器！
Inspection! Arms!
把鼻子伸直.
Stick your nose out.
这样？ -对了
Like this? - That's right.
鼻孔太脏了
A dusty muzzle.
士兵，记住，战场上，鼻子能救你的命
Soldier, remember, in battle, that trunk can save your life.
好好照顾它，士兵 - 是，长官！
Take good care of it, my man  - Yes, sir!
很好，继续
Very good. Cary on.
再吐点口水把这武器擦的干净些  - 是，长官
Let's have a little more spit and polish on those bayonets. - Yes, sir.
团队精神
Esprit de corps.
我是靠团队精神，获得“王公第五旅”的委任。
That's the way I earned my commission in the Maharajah's fifth pachyderm brigade.
那是在88年，当时... Uh，是不是88年？
Back in '88, it was. Uh, or was it?
又来了。又要说维多利亚十字勋章了
Here it comes. The Victoria Cross bit again.
那时候，我被授予十字勋章...
It was then I received the Victoria Cross...
是因为能勇敢地完成职责
for bravely  above and beyond the call of duty.
那都是过去的事了
Those were the days.
纪律 你们知道，是纪律
Discipline. Discipline was the thing.
塑造了性格，以及所有那一类的东西
Builds character, and all that sort of thing, you know.
噢，噢，说到哪了？ 哦，对。检查
Oh, oh, where was I? Oh, yes. Inspection.
很好
Well, very good.
别咧着嘴傻笑，士兵 这是部队
Wipe off that silly grin, soldier. This is the army.
向前看
Eyes front.
中尉，那发型不符合规定
Lieutenant, that haircut is not regulation.
你不觉得那华而不实吗？
Rather on the gaudy side, don't you think?
这样，这样好多了
There. That's better.
至于你--
And as for you--
哦，你还可以
Oh, there you are.
脚后跟并拢，好不好？儿子
Let's keep those heels together, shall we, son?
好，爸爸。长官
Okay, Pop. Sir.
对，现在好多了。
Yes, now that's better.
噢，新兵，恩？
Well, a new recruit, eh?
我说，你鼻子怎么啦？
I say, what happened to your trunk?
嘿！别那样！
Hey! Stop that!
人兽！ 噢，这是背叛 ！
A man cub! Oh, this is treason!
蓄意破坏! 我不会让我的丛林里出现人兽！
Sabotage! I'll have no man cub in my jungle!
我-这不是你的丛林！-别吵了！别吵了！我来解释一下，哈索
I-It's not your jungle! -Hold it! Hold it! I can explain, Hathi.
哈索上校 如果可以的话，长官
Colonel Hathi, If you please, sir.
哦，好，好 哈索上校
Oh, yes, yes. Colonel Hathi.
恩，人兽是和我在一起的 我正带着他返回人类村庄
Uh, the man cub is with me. I'm taking him back to the man village.
留下来？- 你有了巴吉拉的命令
To stay? - You have the word of Bagheera.
好，记住 大象从不忘事的
Good. And remember, an elephant never forgets.
我不知道现在部队要怎样
I don't know what the army's coming to these days.
那些年轻的傲慢的家伙 他们以为他们是谁？
These young whippersnappers, who do they think they are?
我们继续！ 向右看！
Let's get on with it! Right face!
前进！
Forward march!
亲爱的，你没忘记什么吧？
Dear, haven't you forgotten something?
废话，威尼弗雷德老太婆 大象从不忘事的
Nonsense, Winifred old girl. An elephant never forgets.
哦，你惟独忘记了我们的儿子
Well, you just forgot our son.
恩，恩，儿子--儿子？
Uh, uh, son-- Son?
儿子！噢，对，对呀，对呀！ 说得对
Son! Oh, yes, yeah, yeah! Quite right.
向后转！齐步走！
To the rear! March!
我长大后，我要当上校，就象我爸爸那——
When I grow up, I'm gonna be a Colonel, just like my--
我说过一次，就要和说过一千次一样——-噢！
If I've told you once, I've told you a thousand times-- Oh!
爸爸！小心！
Pop! Look out!
哎，爸爸，你忘了说“立定”了
Gee, Pop, you forgot to say "halt."
他说过大象从不忘事的
He said an elephant never forgets.
这并不好笑
It's not funny.
趁其他什么事情发生前 立即离开这
Now let's get out of here quick before anything else happens.
巴吉拉！我们要去哪里？
Bagheera! Where are we goin'?
你就要回到人类村庄
You're going back to the man village right now.
我不想去 -噢，你非去不可
I'm not going  - Oh, yes, you are!
我就待在这里！
I'm staying right here!
就算我拖着你走，你也得走
You're going if I have to drag you every step of the way.
让我走，你-- - 你放开我！
Let go, you- - You let go of me!
哦，就这样定了
Oh, that does it.
我受够了，人兽！
I've had it, man cub!
从现在开始，你一个人好自为之！
From now on, you're on your own alone!
别担心我
Don't worry about me.
愚蠢的人兽
Foolish man cub.
嘟-哔 嘟-哔 嘟-哔 嘟-哔
Doo-bee doo-bee doo-bee-dee-doo
哦，嘟—吧—的—嘟 对，嘟—吧—的—嘟
Well, it'sa doo-bah-dee-doo Yes, it'sa doo-bah-dee-doo
我说的是嘟—哔 嘟—哔，嘟—哔 嘟—哔，嘟—哔—嘟—哔
l mean a doo-bee doo-bee, doo-bee doo-bee, doo-bee-dee-doo
和—
And with--
好吧，现在
Well, now.
看看这是什么呢？
What have we here?
嘿，多有趣的小—
Hey, what a funny little bit of a--
噢！ - 走开！
Oh! - Go away!
哦，小男孩，这个林子里我啥都见过了
Oh, boy, I've seen everything in these woods.
呼！我说什么来着？ 多么可爱的家伙
Hoo! What have I run on? What a pretty thing this is.
别理我  - 好
Leave me alone  - Well, now.
多么可爱的大话! 小家伙
That's pretty big talk, little britches.
我够大了
I'm big enough.
遗憾啊，嘿，小孩, 你需要帮助
Pitiful. Hey, kid, you need help.
老布鲁来教你怎样像熊一样打架
And old Baloo's gonna learn you to fight like a bear.
来吧，我来示范
Now come on, I'm gonna show you.
对！
Yeah!
好吧，孩子，放松。完全放松然后开始晃动身体
All right, now, kid, loosen up. Get real loose and then start to weave.
晃动一点点 现在开始移动! 就这样!
Weave a little. Now move! That's it!
现在，给我一个熊的咆哮 吓唬我
Now give me a big bear growl. Scare me.
哦，男孩
Oh, boy.
我说的是像头大熊
I'm talkin' about like a big bear.
他遇到麻烦了！ 咳，我—我不应该留下他一个人的
He's in trouble! Why, I-I shouldn't have left him alone.
一个大的咆哮，用尽全身的力气 - 感觉怎么样？
A big one. Right from your toes  - How's that?
对，你学会了，孩子 - 噢，不！是布鲁
Yeah, you're gettin' it, kid  - Oh, no! It's Baloo.
那个无能的愚蠢的丛林流浪汉
That shiftless, stupid jungle bum.
左右晃动，寻找空当.
Weave about now and look for an opening.
继续前进，继续-
Keep movin'. Keep--
做得好，你学会了，孩子 再来，就这样
Yeah, you're gettin' it, kid. Come on, that's it.
他棒极了
He's a dandy.
真是个好老师, 老铁爪
Fine teacher you are, old iron paws.
哦，谢谢，巴吉拉 - 恩，告诉我，告诉我，恩...
Oh, thanks, Bagheera  - Eh, tell me, tell me, uh...
你把你的学生撞晕之后, uh, 你还指望他记住你教的吗？恩？
after you knock your pupil senseless, uh, how do you expect him to remember the lesson? Hmm?
这个, 我-- 我, uh-- 这个, 我没想要把他摔那么重
Well, I-- I, uh-- Well, I didn't mean to lay it on him so hard.
我没伤着, 挺好的
I'm not hurt. I'm all right.
我比有些人想象的要强壮
I'm a lot tougher than some people think.
你最好相信这点
You better believe it.
我们再来一次，我要你一直绕圈，要不然我又要撞到你的背了
Now let's go once more.Now I want you to keep circlin' or I'm gonna knock your roof in again.
你要不停地动
You better keep movin'.
嘿! 正好打在我下巴上！
Hey! Right on the button.
不，不，不, 你弄得我很痒
No, no-no, no-no. Now you're ticklin'.
不！不。我们别在丛林里这样
No! No. N-N-Now, now we don't do that here in the jungle.
不，弄得我很痒 我-我受不了这么痒
No, you're ticklin'. I-I can't stand that ticklin'.
救命，巴吉拉！- 噢，孩子，那是他想要的，使劲挠
Help, Bagheera! - Oh, boy, that's all he needs. More confidence.
投降，布鲁？ - 跟你说，我投降
Give up, Baloo? - I give up, I told ya.
嚯！嘿！
Ooh! I give-- Hey!
你知道了？你是对的，孩子。 他们叫你什么？
You know somethin'? You're all right, kid. What do they call you?
毛戈力。他马上就要回人类村庄了
Mowgli. And he's going back to the man village right now.
人类的村子? 他们会毁了他，他们会把他变回一个"人"
Man village? They'll ruin him. They'll make a man out of him.
哦，布鲁，我要和你待在这
Oh, Baloo, I wanna stay here with you.
那当然
Certainly you do.
噢？你觉得他怎么活下去？
Oh? And just how do you think he will survive?
你觉得他-—— 你指什么，你觉得他——
"How do you think he will--" What do you mean, "How do you think he--"
他和我在一起，不是吗？ 我会教给他我知道的一切
He's with me, ain't he? And I'll learn him all I know.
哦，最好不要太久
Well, that shouldn't take too long.
看，就像这样 小不点
Look, now it's like this, little britches.
你要做的一切是——
All you've gotta do is--
寻找最起码的生活必需品  最起码的生活必需品
Look forthe bare necessities  The simple bare necessities
忘记你的恐惧和矛盾
Forget about your worries And your strife
我的意思是，最基本的需要，是天性中的东西
I mean the bare necessities are Mother Nature's recipes
生命中本能的需要
That bring the bare necessities of life
不管我逛到哪儿,晃到哪儿
Wherever I wander Wherever I roam
最喜欢的仍是我的家
I couldn't be fonder of my big home
蜜蜂在花丛中嗡嗡，为我酿蜜
The bee sare buzzin' in the tree to make some honey just for me
你往石头和植物下面看
When you look under the rocks and plants
看一眼那些可爱的蚂蚁
And take a glance at the fancy ants
或许可以尝几个
Then maybe try a few
你吃蚂蚁吗？
You eat ants?
你最好相信，你会喜欢上它们在你舌头上爬来爬去的感觉
You better believe it. And you're gonna love the way they tickle.
毛戈力，小心！
Mowgli, look out!
生活必需品会有的 - 什么时候会有？
The bare necessities of life will come to you - But when?
会有的
They'll come to you
寻找最起码的生活必需品 那最起码的必需品
Look for the bare necessities The simple bare necessities
忘记你的恐惧和矛盾
Forget about your worries And your strife
我是说最基本的需要
I mean the bare necessities
这就是一头熊为什么可以逍遥自在
That's why a bear can rest at ease
只需要那最起码的生活必需品
With just the bare necessities Of life
当你摘仙人掌
Now when you pick a paw paw
或者刺梨 - 哎哟！
Or a prickly pear - Ow!
你的手掌被刺到了 下次要小心
And you prick a raw paw Well, next time, beware
不要直接用手掌
Don't pick the prickly pear By the paw
摘梨时 试着用你的指甲
When you pick a pear Try to use the claw
不过摘比较大的果子的时候,不要用你的指甲
But you don't need to use the claw When you pick a pear of the big paw paw
我说清楚了吗? - 真神。谢谢。布鲁
Have I given you a clue? - Golly. Thanks, Baloo.
木瓜
Pawpaw.
什么玩意儿
Of all the silly gibberish.
好了，布吉, 把它打下来
Come on, Baghee, get with the beat.
生活必需品会有的 - 我会有的!！
The bare necessities of life will come to you - They'll come to me!
你会有的
They'll come to you
抓上面那儿 肩膀左边，毛戈力？
How 'bout scratchin' that ol' left shoulder while you're up there, Mowgli?
头低下一点 在那，就在那。对了。
Now just a hair lower. There. Right there. That's it.
哦！太舒服了
Oh! This is beautiful.
不错。孩子，我们要上树 痛痛快快的搔搔
That's good. Kid, we've got to get to a tree. This calls for some big scratchin'.
你太有趣了。布鲁
You're lots of fun, Baloo.
就在这上面。耶！
Right on it. Yeah!
真舒服
That's delicious.
有那么一点--
Just a little bit--
耶！
Yeah!
耶
Yeah.
哦，--朋友, 这才是真正的活着
Oh, man, this is really livin'.
只要试着放松
So just try and relax.
耶。冷静下来
Yeah. Cool it.
我家后院的瀑布
Fall apart in my backyard.
让我来告诉你,小家伙
'Cause let me tell you somethin', little britches.
如果你象蜜蜂一样
If you act like that bee acts...
恩，你干得太辛苦了
uh-uh, you're workin' too hard.
不花费时间四处寻找...
And don't spend your time lookin' around...
那些你想要却得不到的东西
for something you want that can't be found.
当你发现没有它，你可以照样过，就会不再想它
When you find out you can live without it and go along not thinkin' about it
我来告诉你个真理
I'll tell you somethin' true
你将拥有生活必需品
The bare necessities of life will come to you
我投降, 我希望他会一直好运气
I give up. Well, I hope his luck holds out.
毛戈力，你来唱一下,怎么样?
Mowgli, how 'bout you sing?
寻找最基本的需要 最基本的需要
Look for the bare necessities The simple bare necessities
忘记你的担忧和矛盾 - 耶，朋友
Forget about your worries and your strife  - Yeah, man.
我是说最基本的需要
I mean the bare necessities
那就是为什么熊可以逍遥自在
That's why a bear can rest at ease
虽然仅仅满足最基本的需要
With just the bare necessities of life
耶！- 只要满足最基本的需要
Yeah!- With just the bare necessities of life
耶！朋友！
Yeah, man!
太美了 多么和谐的丛林
Beautiful! That's real jungle harmony.
我喜欢做一头熊。 - 这才是我的好孩子。
I like being a bear  - That's my boy.
你会长成一头大熊. 为啥呢, 你唱歌都象熊
And you're gonna make one swell bear. Why, you even sing like one.
嘿，毛戈力，把那只老坏的苍蝇--
Hey, Mowgli, how 'bout you flickin' that old, mean fly...
从你熊爸爸的鼻子上赶走,怎么样?
of fo' your papa bear's nose?
哎哟！
Ouch!
孩子, 在你赶苍蝇的时候, 你真是--
Boy, when you flick a fly, you really--
怎么是你这个塌鼻子,小眼睛,贼头贼脑的家伙
Why you flat-nosed, little-eyed, flaky creep!
嘿！放开我!
Hey! Let go of me!
把你们的脏手从我孩子身上拿开!
Take your flea-pickin' hands of fo' my cub!
来啊,把他带走啊,气急败坏的家伙!
Come on and get him, champ!
他不是气急. 他是内急! - 布鲁！
He ain't no champ. He's a chump! - Baloo!
急得脑门都红了!
Yeah! A big hothead!
耶！你们自找的. 我要--
Okay, you guys asked for it. I'll--
那可以让他清醒一下.
That'll cool him off.
把孩子还给我!
Gimme back my man cub!
他在这儿,来拿啊!
Here he is. Come and get him!
那就是一头熊怎样做到悠闲自在的
That's how a bear can rest at ease.
这儿还有些生活必需品.
Here's some bare necessities.
有种再试试,你们--
Now just try that again, you--
你用什么打他的，孩子？ - 一个生活必需品
What's that you hit him with, son? - That was a bare necessity.
小心着点, 臭猴子, 放开他,否则我给你们尾巴打上结--
Look, monk, you turn him loose or I'll jerk a knot in your tail--
我们投降吧！ 他来了！
We give up! Here he comes!
布鲁！抓住我！
Baloo! Catch me!
布鲁！-退后！退后！再快点! 再快点! 再快点!
Baloo!- Back up! Back up! Faster! Faster! Faster!
熊下去咯,毛毛都滚掉了!
A rolling bear gathers no hair!
布鲁！救救我! 布鲁，他们要带走我！
Baloo! Help me! Baloo, they're carrying me away!
巴吉拉！
Bagheera!
Well, 有情况
Well, it's happened.
比我预想的要迟点,但还是发生了
Took a little longer than I thought,but it's happened.
巴吉拉！
Bagheera!
Oh, 你听到了吗?
Oh, you heard me, huh?
毛戈力。毛戈力！
Mowgli. Mowgli!
好吧，出什么事了？ 毛戈力在哪里？
All right, what happened? Where's Mowgli?
他们偷袭了我，一大群猴子
They ambushed me. Thousands of'em.
我左直拳. 右摆拳. 然后--
I jabbed with my left. Then I swung with a right. And then I let--
哦，最后一遍，毛戈力到底怎么啦？
Oh, for the last time, what happened to Mowgli?
正如我跟你说的, 那群猴子把他抓走了
Like I told ya, them mangy monkeys carried him off.
古代废墟?哦，我不敢想象当他遇到它们的大王,会发生什么
The ancient ruins.Oh, I hate to think what'll happen when he meets that king of theirs.
我们抓到他了，路易王！我们抓到他了,抓到他了!
We got him, King Louie!- Here he is. Man, we got him. We got him!
你就是人兽。真疯狂！
So you're the man cub. Crazy.
我可没有你那么疯 把我放下来!
I'm not as crazy as you are. Put me down!
你不会轻一点啊!
You cut that out!
冷静点, 孩子，放松
Cool it, boy.Unwind yourself.
来, 让我们握握手, 我的近亲
Now come on,let's shake, cousin.
你们把我抓来想干嘛?
What do you want me for?
我听说…先吃个香蕉
Word has grabbed my royal ear--Have a banana--
说你想留在丛林里
that you wanna stay in the jungle.
留在丛林里? 确实是
Stay in the jungle? I sure do.
好吧，很好。 老路易王--
Well, good. And old King Louie--
就是我-- 可以帮你实现愿望
That's me-- can fix it for you.
吃两个香蕉吧
Have two bananas.
我们商量一下好吗？- 好，先生
Have we got a deal? - Yes, sir.
我会做-- 我会做任何事情,为了留在从林里
I'll do-- I'll do anything to stay in the jungle.
那么
Well, then.
我会把话给你说清楚
I'll lay it on the line for you.
现在我是时髦之王 丛林中的VIP
Now I'm the king of the swingers Oh, the jungle VlP
我已经到达了极至 不得不停下来
I've reached the top And had to stop
这让我很烦恼
And that's what's botherin' me
我想成为一个人类，一个人，在城里游荡
I wanna be a man, man cub And stroll right into town
像其他人类那样 我已经厌倦了做猴子
And be just like the other men I'm tired of monkeyin' around
哦，哦-必-嘟
Oh, ooh-bee-doo
我要像你一样
I wanna be like you
我要像你那样走路  像你那样说话
I wanna walk like you Talk like you too
你知道这是真的
You see it's true
像我这样一个猴子
An ape like me
也能学会做一个人
Can learn to be human too
什么?
What?
嘻， 路易老兄，你干得不错
Gee, Cousin Louie, you're doin' real good.
现在，协议里你应该做的事情就是，表兄
Now here's your part of the deal, cuz.
把人类生火的秘密告诉我
Lay the secret on me of man's red fire.
但是我不知道怎样生火
But I don't know how to make fire.
别想耍我, 小孩子 我们已经达成过协议
Now don't try to kid me, man cub I made a deal with you
我想要的就是人类那红色的火焰
What I desire Is man's red fire
让我梦想成真
To make my dream come true
把秘密告诉我，人兽 说吧，告诉我怎么做
Now give me the secret, man cub Come on, clue me what to do
给我火焰的力量
Give me the power of man's red flower
让我能像你一样
So I can be like you
火？这就是那恶棍想要的东西
Fire? So that's what that scoundrel's after.
我会把它撕成碎片，狠狠揍它
I'll tear him limb from limb. I'll beat him.
我会-- 我会--
I'll-- I'll--
耶！
Yeah!
朋友, 多好的节奏
Well, man, what a beat.
你可以停止那愚蠢的节奏听我说吗?
Will you stop that silly beat business and listen?
要用脑子,不要蛮干
This will take brains, not brawn.
你最好相信---我是智勇双全的
You better believe it, and I'm loaded with both.
你不能好好听着? - 哦，好，好
Will you listen?- Oh. Yeah, yeah.
现在, 你去制造一场混乱...
Now, while you create a disturbance...
我趁机营救毛戈力 明白了吗？
I'll rescue Mowgli. Got that?
我出发了, 朋友
I'm gone, man. Solid gone.
不是现在，布鲁！
Not yet, Baloo!
嘿！
Hey!
疯狂吧，宝贝！
Get mad, baby.
你  我想跟你一样
You, l wanna be like you
像你那样走路 像你那样说话
l wanna walk like you Talk like you too
你明白那是真的
You see it's true
像我这样的
Someone like me
可以学会做个像我这样的人
Can learn to be Like someone like me
带我回家，爸爸！
Take me home, daddy!
可以学做个像你一样的人
Can learn to be Like someone like you
再来一次! - 耶，可以学会---
One more time! - Yeah, can learn to be
像我一样的人
Like someone like me
朋友！-是布鲁那头熊！
Man! - It's Baloo, the bear!
对，是他！那个大块头怎么在那里？
Yeah, that's him! How'd that square get in there?
布鲁，是你！
Baloo, it's you!
那就是我所说的摇摆舞会
Man, that's what I call a swingin' party.
此外,布鲁
And furthermore, Baloo...
毛戈力似乎具有人类的制造麻烦的能力
Mowgli seems to have man's ability to get into trouble.
你的影响还没有真正地--
And your influence hasn't been exactly--
嘘，小声些 你会吵醒小家伙的
Shh. Keep it down. You're gonna wake up little buddy.
嗒 - 今天是个大日子
Dah  - Well, he's had a big day.
真是个成功的演出
It was a real sockaroo.
你知道，要学我不容易
You know, it ain't easy learnin' to be like me.
呸！ 表现很糟糕
Pah! A disgraceful performance.
想起那些招人讨厌的，多动症的猴子
Associating with those undesirable, scatterbrained apes.
恩，我希望毛戈力从你那里学到了点什么
Unh. I hope Mowgli learned something from that experience.
咕哔 - 嘟哔, 嘟哔-嘟.
Scooby-dooby, dooby-doo.
那是我孩子
That's my boy.
噢，胡说
Oh, nonsense.
布鲁
Baloo.
过来， 我有话要跟你说
Over here. I'd like to have a word with you.
话? 你还想说什么?
A word? You gonna talk some more?
好吧，怎么啦，巴吉拉？
All right, what's up, Bagheera?
布鲁--
Baloo...
这人兽必须回到人类的村庄
the man cub must go back to the man village.
丛林不是他应该呆的地方
The jungle is not the place for him.
我在丛林中长大, 看看我
I grew up in the jungle. Take a look at me.
对，看看你自己
Yes, just look at yourself.
看看那只眼睛
Look at that eye.
是，很漂亮，不是吗?
Yeah. It's beautiful, ain't it?
老实说, 你的样子很衰
Yeah. Frankly, you're a disreputable sight.
你还不如一篮水果呢
Well, you don't look exactly like a basket off ruit yourself.
欧。
Ohh.
布鲁，你不能收养毛戈力
Baloo, you can't adopt Mowgli as your son.
为什么不能？
Why not?
我该怎么说? 它--布鲁--
H-H-How can I put it? It-- Baloo...
物以类聚
birds of a feather should flock together.
你不会和豹结婚，对吗？
You wouldn't marry a panther, would you?
我不知道
I don't know.
想了想,从没有一只豹子跟我谈过这事儿
Come to think of it, no panther ever asked me.
不,布鲁，你-你能不能严肃点？
No. Baloo, you-you've got to be serious about this.
哦，别担心。布鲁。别担心
Oh, stop woryin', Baghee. Stop woryin'.
我会照顾他的
I'll take care of him.
是的，就像猴子们绑架他时你做的那样？
Yes. Like you did when the monkeys kidnapped him, huh?
谁没有犯错的时候? - 不能在丛林里犯错
Can't a guy make one mistake? - Not in the jungle.
还有一件事
And another thing.
迟早, 毛戈力会碰到歇尔可汗
Sooner or later, Mowgli will meet Shere Khan.
那只老虎? 它为什么和这孩子作对?
The tiger? What's he got against the kid?
它跟人类有仇 你知道的
He hates man with a vengeance. You know that.
因为他害怕人类的枪和火
Because he fears man's gun and man's fire.
但是小毛戈力没有那些东西
But little Mowgli don't have those things.
歇尔可汗不会等到他有那些东西
Shere Khan won't wait until he does.
它会在毛戈力年幼无助的时候抓住他
He'll get Mowgli while he's young and helpless.
只要这么一下… -不
Just one swipe and-- - No.
好啦--好啦，我们该怎么办？
Well-- Well, what are we gonna do?
我们要做对这孩子最有利的事情 -你最好相信这点
We'll do what's best for the boy - You better believe it.
你说吧,我一定照做
You name it, and I'll do it.
很好. 把毛戈力送回人类村庄
Good. Then make Mowgli go to the man village.
你疯了吗？我答应过他--
Are you out of your mind? I promised him...
它可以留在这儿,和我一起在丛林里
he could stay here in the jungle with me.
这就是关键 只要他留下来和你在一起---
Well, that's just the point. As long as he remains with you...
就很危险,这取决于你
he's in danger, so it's up to you.
为什么是我？ - 因--因--因为他不听我的
Why me? - Be-Be-Because he won't listen to me.
我爱那孩子
I love that kid.
我爱他就像我自己的孩子
I love him like he was my own cub.
那么想想什么对毛戈力最好，而不是对你
Then think of what's best for Mowgli and not yourself.
能否-那么, 我可以等到天亮再....?
Uh, well, can't-- Well, can't I wait until morning?
已经天亮了
It's morning now.
来吧，布鲁
Go on, Baloo.
恩--
Uh--
哦，孩子
Oh, boy.
毛戈力，毛戈力
Mowgli. Mowgli.
该起床了
Uh, it's time to get up.
哦。你好，布鲁
Oh. Hi, Baloo.
把那些瞌睡虫从你眼睛里赶走
Hi. Hey, rub that old sleep out of your eyes.
你和我，我们还有很长一段路要走
You and me, uh, we got a long walk ahead of us.
大熊，我们在一起会有很多快乐
Swell. Gee, we'll have lots of fun together.
那当然 对了，恩--
Sure. Yeah. Yeah. Uh--
好吧, 上路吧, 孩子
All right, let's hit the trail, kid.
回见 恩，巴吉拉.
See ya around, uh, Bagheera.
再见，巴吉拉
Well, goodbye, Bagheera.
布鲁和我，我们有很多事情要做
Me and Baloo, we've got things to do.
再见, 孩子，祝你好运
Goodbye, man cub. And good luck.
来吧，布鲁 我们要做的是——
Come on, Baloo. All we gotta do is--
寻找生活必需品
Look for the bare necessities
一些生活必需品
Some good old bare necessities
忘记你的担忧和矛盾
Forget about your worries And your strife
我是说生活必需品
l mean the bare necessities
那就是为什么熊可以逍遥自在
That's why a bear can rest at ease
仅仅拥有生活必需品
With just the bare necessities of life
耶，我会生活在这丛林里
Yeah I'll live here in the jungle
一辈子, 耶
All my life Yeah, man
我喜欢做一只熊
I like bein' a bear.
我们在往哪儿走，布鲁？ -哦，恩，去--，恩--
Where we goin', Baloo? - Well, uh, it's, uh--
恩，哦，这次去一个新地方 恩——
Um, well, it's sort of new and, uh--
哦，我不在意，只要和你在一起.
Oh, I don't care,as long as I'm with you.
毛戈力，恩，听着, 伙计, 恩--
Mowgli, uh, look, buddy, uh...
有些事情我得告诉你.
there's somethin' I gotta tell ya.
告诉我什么，布鲁？
Tell me what, Baloo?
唉
Gee whiz.
老布鲁该怎么说? 这, uh--
Now how did old Baghee put it? It's, uh--
恩，恩，毛戈力？
Uh, uh, Mowgli?
哈！你不会娶一头豹子, 是不是?
Ha! You wouldn't marry a panther, would you?
我不知道你在说什么
Gee, I don't even know what you're talkin' about.
毛戈力，你没有认识到你是一个人类吗?
Mowgli, don't you realize that you're a human?
我不再是了，布鲁。我是一头熊，就像你一样。
I'm not any more, Baloo. I'm a bear like you.
小伙计, 来,听我说.
Little buddy, look, listen to me.
来吧，来吧，布鲁  - 毛戈力，停下，停下
Come on. Come on, Baloo - Now, Mowgli, stop it now.
别乱跑. 我-我想跟你好好谈谈
Now hold still. I-I want to tell you something.
现在听我说
Now listen to me.
怎么啦。老熊爸爸？ 听着 -毛戈力---
What's the matter, old Papa Bear? - Look, Mowgli...
我要告诉你，我一上午都在想告诉你.
I been tyin' to tell ya. I been tyin' all morning to tell ya.
我要把你送回人类的村子
I've got to take you back to the man village.
人类村庄！- 孩子，听我说--
The man village! - Now look, kid...
我可以解释--- 可是, 你说我们是伙伴.
I can explain, and-- - But, but you said we were partners.
相信我，孩子，我-我-我-- -你就像，就像老巴吉拉！
Now believe me, kid, I-I-I-- - You're just like, like old Bagheera!
就一会儿，太过分了
Now just a minute. That's goin' too far.
嘿，毛戈力， 你要去哪里？
Hey, Mowgli, where you goin'?
等一等！站住！
Wait a minute! Stop!
等等！
Wait!
等等！听听老布鲁的
Wait! Listen to old Baloo.
毛戈力，毛戈力！
Mowgli. Mowgli!
毛戈力！
Mowgli!
- 毛戈力。毛戈力！- 发生什么了?
- Mowgli. Mowgli! - Now what's happened?
你, 你, 你大概不会相信我, 巴吉拉---
Well, you, you, you're not gonna believe me, Bagheera...
可是, 我照你说的那样说了, 然后他就跑了.
but look, now I used the same words you did, and he ran out on me.
好啦，别光站在那儿
Well, don't just stand there.
我们分头找吧。我们-- 我们一定要找到他
Let's separate.We-- We've got to find him.
噢，如果这小家伙出了什么事---
Oh, if anything happens to that little guy...
我永远不能原谅我自己
I'll never forgive myself.
我一定要找到他， 毛戈力！
I gotta find him. Mowgli!
毛戈力！
Mowgli.
嘿，二，三，四
Hup, two, three, four
不松劲 二，三
Keep it up Two, three
真不走运
What beastly luck.
那个可笑的哈索上校真讨厌
Confound that ridiculous Colonel Hathi.
部队, 安静
Company, sound off.
我们到处行军
Oh, we march from here to there
不论到哪儿
And it doesn't matter where
你可以听到我们穿过灌木丛
You can hear us push through the deepest bush
嘿，二，三，四
Hup, two, three, four
伴随军乐曲
With a military air
丛林巡逻
The jungle patrol.
我们是无敌雄师
We're a cracker jack brigade
在阅兵场上
On a pachyderm parade
但我们宁愿在泥沼里穿行
But we'd rather stroll to a waterhole
嘿，二，三，四
Hup, two, three, four
在树荫下休息
For a furlough in the shade
停下! 等--等一会
Stop! W-Wait a minute.
立定！
Halt!
是谁说的立定？这里由我发令！
Who said halt? I give the commands around here.
大声说，你是谁？ - 哦，是我，上校
Now speak up. Who was it? - Oh, it was me, Colonel.
你什么意思, 先生, 冒用我的命令?
What do you mean, sir,taking over my command?
非常无礼, 你知道 -喔，上校, 我--我很抱歉...
Highly irregular, you know  - Oh, Colonel, I-I'm sorry...
可是, 可是我需要你的帮助  -哦，没门
but, but I need your help  - Oh, absolutely impossible.
我们在越野行军 - 但是这很紧急，上校
We're on a cross-county march  - But it's an emergency, Colonel.
一定要找到那个人兽 - 人兽？什么人兽？
The man cub must be found - Man cub? What man cub?
真有趣  - 我正要送回人类村庄的那个
How interesting  -The one I was taking to the man village.
好, 那是他应该呆的地方.
Good. That's where he belongs.
先生,如果你不介意...
Now, sir, If you don't mind...
我们要继续行军了
we'd like to get on with the march.
不，不，不，你 你不了解，哈索
No, no, no, you, you don't understand, Hathi.
他走丢了，他跑了
He is lost. He ran away.
真不错
How delightful.
好吧，自以为是的年轻人经常如此
Well, serves the young whippersnapper right.
但是，但是，歇尔可汗，那只可怕的老虎--
But, but Shere Khan, the tiger--
他一定会找到这个人兽踪迹的
He's sure to pick up the man cub's trail.
歇尔可汗？胡说, 伙计
Shere Khan. Nonsense, old boy.
这几英里范围内不会出现歇尔可汗
Shere Khan isn't within miles of here.
哦，抱歉，巴吉拉
Oh, sorry, Bagheera.
战争的命运, 诸如此类的事,你知道
Fortunes of war, and all that sort of thing, you know.
够了！够了！
This has gone far enough. Far enough.
等等, 你这个饶舌的老家伙
Now just a minute, you pompous old windbag.
威尼弗雷德！你不在队伍中，在干什么？
Winifred! What are you doing out of ranks?
别管这个！
Never mind.
你要把我们的孩子怎么样——
How would you like to have our boy...
把他一个人丢在丛林中？
lost and alone in the jungle?
我们的儿子？好吧--
Our son? W-Well--
但是，威尼弗雷德老太婆，那完全不一样
But, Winifred old girl, that's an entirely different matter.
哼！- 不一样，完全不一样
Huh! - Different, entirely.
那个小男孩跟我们的儿子没有两样
That little boy is no different than our own son.
现在你帮忙找到他，否则我接管指挥权
Now you help find him, or I'm taking over command.
什么！一头母象来领导我的部队?
What! A female leading my herd?
太可笑了
Utterly preposterous.
爸爸？那个人兽和我是好朋友
Pop? The man cub and I are friends.
如果我们不找到他，他会受到伤害的
He'll get hurt If we don't find him.
求你了，爸爸？长官 求你了？
Please, Pop? Sir? Please?
别担心，儿子。
Now don't you worry, son.
你老爸早就有主意了
Your father had a plan in mind all the time.
当然有。
Sure you did.
士兵们！ 全队，向左转！
Troopers! Company, left face!
志愿参加一项特殊任务的——
Volunteers for a special mission...
向前一步走
will step one pace forward.
那是我希望看到的，忠于职责
That's what I like to see. Devotion to duty.
现在，你们志愿者要去找一个迷路的人兽
Now, you volunteers will find the lost man cub.
哦，谢谢你，上校。 没时间可浪费了
Oh, thank you, Colonel. Now there's no time to lose.
是的，是的 好吧，号手…
Yes, yes. Well, bugler.
一看见人兽， 你就吹号…
When the man cub is sighted, you will sound your trumpet...
三次  -是，长官
three times  - Yes, sir.
不是现在，士兵
Not now, soldier.
对不起，长官
Sorry, sir.
中尉，我们的策略将出其不意
Lieutenant, our strategy shall be the element of surprise.
你带一个班——
You will take one squad...
搜寻右侧  -是，长官
and cover the right flank  - Yes, sir.
我带另一个班——
And I shall lead the other squad...
在左侧
on the left flank.
很好。全队——
Very well. Company...
向前走！
forward march!
出其不意?
Element of surprise?
哦，我说。
Oh, I say.
那么现在，我要去和那个迷路的小人兽会合了
And now for my rendezvous with the little lost man cub.
喀！是你！
Kaa! It's you!
对，人兽
Yes, man cub.
很高兴又见到你
So nice to see you again.
哦，走开 让我一个人呆着
Oh, go away. Leave me alone.
让我看看你
Let me look at you.
不想让我看你?
You don't want me to look at you?
那你看我吧
Then you look at me.
不，先生，我知道你要干什么，咯——
No, sir. I know what you're tryin' to do, Kaa--
你知道？恩，我是说——
You do? Uh, I mean...
你不相信我 -不
you don't trust me  - No.
那我可就没法帮你了
Then there's nothing I can do to help.
你想帮我?
You wanna help me?
当然了
Certainly.
我看得出来你从来没有离开过这个丛林
I can see to it that you never have to leave this jungle.
你怎么知道?
How could you do that?
恩？哦，我有自己的——
Hmm? Oh, I have my own...
小窍门
subtle little ways.
但是首先 你得相信我
But first, you must trust me.
我不再相信任何人了
I don't trust anyone any more.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我不像那些叫做——
I'm not like those so-called...
你那些只能共安乐的朋友
fair-weather friends of yours.
你可以相信我
You can believe in me.
信任我
Trust in me
就信我
Just in me
闭上眼睛
Shut your eyes
相信我
And trust in me
安静别动
Hold still, please.
你可以睡觉
You can sleep
安然无恙
Safe and sound
知道我在
Knowing I
在身边
Am around
安静地睡吧
Slip into silent slumber
在银色的薄雾上航行
Sail on a silver mist
感到慢慢的、稳稳的
SlowIy and sure lyyoursenses
不要反抗
Will cease to resist
你在打呼噜
You're snoring.
对不起
Sorry.
相信我
Trust in me
就信我
And just in me
闭上眼睛
Shut your eyes
相信我
And trust in me
哦，什么人？
Oh, now what?
我就来
I'll be right down.
谁呀？谁呀？是谁？
Yes? Yes? Who is it?
是我，歇尔可汗
It's me, Shere Khan.
不介意的话，我有话要和你说
I'd like a word with you If you don't mind.
歇尔可汗
Shere Khan.
太惊奇了
What a surprise.
对，不是吗？
Yes, isn't it?
我顺便路过 请原谅我打扰了
I just dropped by. Forgive me if I've interrupted anything.
不，不，不 根本不
Oh, no, no, nothing at all.
我想你可能正缠绕着什么人做游戏
I thought perhaps you were entertaining someone up there in your coils.
缠着？什么人？  哦。没有
Coils? Someone? Oh, no.
我刚才只是蜷着身子在午休
I was just curling up for my siesta.
可是你在向谁唱歌？是谁，喀？
But you were singing to someone. Who is it, Kaa?
恩，谁？没有谁，没有谁
Uh, who? Oh, no.
哦，我只是唱给-恩，自己听
Well, I was just singing, uh, to myself.
真的 -对，对，你知道-
Indeed  - Yes. Yes, you see...
我的鼻子出了点毛病
I have trouble with my sinuses.
真可怜  - 哦，你不知道
What a pity  - Oh, you have no idea.
那简直难受极了
It's simply terrible.
我不能吃 不能睡
I can't eat. I can't sleep.
所以我给自己唱歌
So I sing myself to sleep.
你知道的，自我催眠
You know, self-hypnosis.
让我给你演示一下
Let me show you how it works.
哦，相信我
Ah, trust in me
不, 我已经烦了. 我没时间听你的那些胡说八道.
No, I can't be bothered with that. I have no time for that sort of nonsense.
另外找个时间怎么样?
Some other time perhaps?
也许吧。现在我在找一个人兽
Perhaps. But at the moment I am searching for a man cub.
人兽？什么人兽？
Man cub? What man cub?
那个迷路的人兽
The one who's lost.
你猜他现在可能在哪？
Now where do you suppose he could be?
搜我身! - 好主意
Search me. - That's an excellent idea.
我肯定你不介意让我看看你蜷着的身子, 是吧 喀？
I'm sure you wouldn't mind showing me your coils, would you, Kaa?
恩，当然不介意
Uh, certainly not.
什么也没有
Nothing here.
这也没有
And nothing in here.
我的鼻子
My sinuses.
恩，确实是没有
Hmm. Indeed.
中间那部分呢?
And now, how about the middle?
中间？
The middle?
哦，中间
Oh, the middle.
中间绝对没有任何东西
Absolutely nothing in the middle.
真的吗？
Really?
好吧，如果你真的碰巧看见人兽——
Well, if you do just happen to see the man cub...
你一定要最先告诉我,明白吗?
you will inform me first, understand?
我明白, 用我的脑袋发誓.
I get the point. Cross my heart, hope to die.
很好
Good show.
现在我要继续去寻找那个无助的小孩
And now I must continue my search for the helpless little lad.
哦，它以为它在愚弄谁?
Ooh, who does he think he's fooling?
"那个无助的小孩."
"The helpless little lad."
他让我发抖.
Ooh, he gives me the shivers.
找那个可怜的无依无靠的男孩
Picking on that poor little helpless boy.
哦，对
Oh, yes.
可怜无助的小男孩
Poor little helpless boy.
你说谎，喀
You told me a lie, Kaa.
你说我可以相信你
You said I could trust you.
你说的对
It's like you said.
你不能相信任何人
You can't trust anyone.
如果我再看到那个小东西...
If I never see that skinny little shrimp again...
我不会再让他跑掉
it will be too soon.
呵，我的尾巴
Ooh, my sacroiliac.
嘿，我们要干什么？
Hey, Flaps, what we gonna do?
我不知道 你想干什么?
I don't know. What you wanna do?
我有主意了! 让我们飞到丛林的东边去
I've got it! Let's flap over to the east side of the jungle.
他们总会搞些活动,狂欢什么的
They've always got a bit of action, a bit of a swingin' scene all right.
噢，别吹牛了, 四处都是死寂一片
Ah, come off it. Things are right dead all over.
你的意思是你希望那些
You mean you wish they were.
很有趣
Very funny.
好吧，我们要做什么？
Okay. So what we gonna do?
我不知道 你想要做什么？
I don't know. What do you wanna do?
你看，弗莱普斯，我先说 “我们要做什么？”
Look, Flaps, first I say, "What we gonna do?"
然后你说, "我不知道,你想干什么?"
Then you say, "I don't know. What you wanna do?"
然后我说，“我们要做什么？” 你说，“你打算干什么？”
Then I say, "What we gonna do?" You say, "What you wanna do?"
"我们干什么?" "你想干什么--"  让我们干点什么!
"What we gonna do?" "What you want--" Let's do something!
好。你想做些什么？
Okay. What you wanna do?
啊呀。 你又来了。又是老一套。
Blimey. There you go again. The same notes again.
我有主意了! 这次我真的有主意了.
I've got it! This time I've really got it.
你有了新主意 那我们接下来干什么？
So you've got it. Then what we gonna do?
别急，伙计。看，看什么向我们走过来了.
Hold it, lads. Look. Look what's coming our way.
嘿，那究竟是什么？
Hey, what in the world is that?
这堆骨头看上去真疯狂
What a crazy-looking bunch of bones.
他们全都自己走过来了
Yeah, and they're all walkin' about by themselves.
是的
Yeah.
所以我们要做什么？ -我不知道
So what we gonna do?  - I don't know.
嘿，别又开始绕嘴
Hey, now don't start that again!
来吧，让我们跟这个小家伙找点乐子...
Come on, lads. Come on. Let's have some fun with this little fella...
这个小笨蛋
this little blokey.
他有鹳一样的腿
Blimey. He's got legs like a stork, he has.
像一只鹳. 但是他没有羽毛,没有
Like a stork. But he ain't got no feathers, he ain't.
说吧，笑吧，我不在乎
Go ahead. Laugh. I don't care.
他怎么啦？ - 我们玩过火了
What's wrong with him? - I think we overdid it.
我们只是开个小玩笑，没别的。
We were just having a bit Of fun, that's all.
哦，你看他，可怜的小家伙
Oh, just look at him. Why, the poor little fella.
你知道, 他一定是倒了霉
You know, he must be down on his luck.
说得对，否则他就不是我们的邻居了
Yeah, or he wouldn't be in our neighbourhood.
嘿，新来的 等一等！嘿！
Hey, new kid, wait a minute! Hey!
让我一个人呆着 - 哦，来吧，怎么啦？
Just leave me alone  - Oh, come on. What's wrong?
你知道, 你看起来像是在这个世界上没有一个朋友..
You know, you look like you haven't got a friend in the world.
我没有 - 你有父母吗?
I haven't  - Haven't you got a mother or a father?
没有，没人愿跟我在一起
No. Nobody wants me around.
哦，我们明白你的感受.
Yeah, we know how you feel.
也没人想和我在一起
Nobody wants us around either.
啊啊，我们看上去有点邋遢,但我们有心
Ah, we may look a bit shabby, but we've got heart.
也有感情
And feelings too.
为了证明这一点,我们邀请你加入我们的小集体
And just to prove it to you, we're gonna let you join our little group.
孩子，我们会让你做一只受人尊敬的秃鹰
Kid, we'd like to make you an honouray vulture.
谢谢，我-我宁可一个人呆着
Thanks, but I-- I'd rather be on my own, alone.
看着, 孩子
Aw, now look, kid.
谁都需要朋友
Eveybody's got to have friends.
嗨，伙计们 我们是他的朋友吗？
Hey, fellas, are we his friends?
我们是你的朋友
We're your friends
我们是你的铁哥们
We're your friends to the bitterend
铁哥们
The bitterend
你孤独时
When you're alone
谁来到你身边
Who comes around
鼓起你的勇气 - 鼓起你的勇气 - 对我们笑笑
To pluck you up - To pluck you up - Give us a smile.
当你沮丧时
When you are down
当你正在外面徘徊
And when you're outside lookin' in
谁为你开门？ -来吧，孩子，我们需要一个男高音
Who's there to open the door  - Come on, kid. We need a tenor.
那就是  - 那就是朋友
That's what - What friends are for
总是渴望伸出
Who's always eager to extend
友谊之手
A friendly claw
那就是朋友
That's what friends are for
当你失去最需要的东西
And when you're lost in dire need
谁闪电般的来到你身边
Who's at your side at lightning speed
我们是最好的朋友
We're friends with every creature comin' down the pike
实际上我们从没遇到过不喜欢的动物
In fact we've never met an animal we didn't like
哈哈，你学会了, 孩子
Ha-ha. You take it, kid.
不喜欢？
Didn't like
你知道我们是朋友
So you can see we're friends
我们是患难中的朋友  -我们是患难中的朋友
We're friends in need  - We're friends in need
患难中的朋友 -患难中的朋友
And friends in need - Friends in need
-是真正的朋友 -是真正的朋友
-Are friends indeed -Are friends indeed
呼，呼 伙计们，放轻松 -我们会保证你安全的
Whoop, whoop. Take it easy, lads.- We'll keep you safe
留神,小心！- 在丛林中
Steady, steady. Watch it! - In the jungle
永远地
Forevermore
那就是朋友的…
That's what friends
作用
Are for
棒极了, 棒极了
Bravo, bravo.
表演棒极了
An extraordinary performance.
谢谢你们帮我抓住了我的猎物
And thank you for detaining my victim.
哦，要--别客气，殿下
Uh, do-don't mention it, Your Highness.
嘘 - 我们离开这
Boo. - Let's get out of here.
给我留点地方!！让路！
Give me room! Gangway!
跑，朋友！快跑！
Run, friend! Run!
跑？我为什么要跑？
Run? Why should I run?
你为什么要跑？
Why should you run?
你难道不知道我是谁?
Could it be possible that you don't know who I am?
我认识你，你是歇尔可汗。
I know you, all right. You're Shere Khan.
好极了,那么你一定也知道...
Precisely. Then you should also know...
所有人看见我都要跑
that everyone runs from Shere Khan.
你吓唬不了我，我不会从任何人身边逃跑
You don't scare me. I won't run from anyone.
奥，你这么小有勇气
Ah. You have spirit for one so small.
这样的勇气应该得到一个公平的比赛机会
And such spirit is deserving of a sporting chance.
现在，我闭上眼睛数到十
Now, I'm going to close my eyes and count to ten.
这会使追捕变得更加有趣...
It makes the chase more interesting...
对我来说
for me.
一，二---
One, two...
三---
three...
四---
four--
你在考验我的耐心
You're tying my patience.
五，六，七，八，九，十！
Five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten!
跑，毛戈力，快跑！
Run, Mowgli. Run!
躲开, 你这个笨蛋
Let go, you big oaf.
别紧张。拿着-- 呜！抓住，抓住
Take it easy. Take it-- Whoo! Ho-Hold it, hold it.
哇。慢一点。呵！约！哇！慢！现在好了。
Whoa. Slow down. Ooh! Yow! Whoa! Slow! Easy now.
呵，噢，孩子，好了
Ooh. Oh, boy. Easy.
他抓住了老虎尾巴，他抓到了
He's got a tiger by the tail, he has.
最好抓得够紧
And he'd better hang on too.
看打, 你这个欺软怕硬的家伙
Take that, ya big bully.
打他, 孩子,再打他, 孩子， 继续!
Let him have it again, kid. Hit him again, kid. Go on!
布鲁！救我！
Baloo! Help me!
谁来救救这孩子
Somebody do somethin' with that kid.
来吧，伙计们
Come on, lads.
他现在安全了
He's safe now.
你可以放开了，布鲁
You can let go, Baloo.
你在开玩笑? 老虎的牙可不是吃素的
Are you kiddin'? There's teeth in the other end.
我要杀了你
I'll kill you for this.
放开我！布鲁需要帮助！
Let go! Baloo needs help!
火! 那是那老虎唯一害怕的
Fire! That's the only thing old Stripes is afraid of.
你去取火，剩下的由我来.
You get the fire. We'll do the rest.
冲啊！-去那边！拳打！脚踢！
Charge! - You there, punch and blow.
滚开,你们这些笨蛋
Stay out of this, you mangy fools.
是，是 它差一点
Yeah, yeah. Missed me a mile, he did.
是！- 是！扯他那亮亮的胡须
Yeah!- Yeah! Pull his blinkin' whiskers.
他是个讨厌的大猫，的确是！
He's a bloomin' pussycat, he is.
看看你的身后,朋友
Look behind you, chum.
他的末日到了
Well, that's the last of him.
老斑毛离开就像一颗燃烧的彗星，的确是
Old Stripes took off like a flaming comet, he did.
来吧. 让我们祝贺我们的朋友
Well, come on. Let's go congratulate our friend.
等等, 伙计们
Hold it, fellas.
现在还不是时候，看
Now's not the time for it. Look.
布鲁？
Baloo?
布鲁，起来啦 哦，请起来啦
Baloo, get up. Oh, please get up.
毛戈力，试着理解
Mowgli, try to understand.
巴吉拉，他怎么啦？
Bagheera, what's the matter with him?
你要勇敢点，就像布鲁那样
You've got to be brave, like Baloo was.
你--你不是说--
You-- You don't mean--
别这样，别这样。布鲁
Oh, no. Baloo.
现在，现在
Now, now.
我理解你的感受
I know how you feel.
但是你必须记住 毛戈力--
But you must remember, Mowgli...
没有哪种更伟大的爱--
greater love hath no one...
比得上为朋友牺牲生命
than he who lays down his life for his friend.
当伟大的功绩被这个丛林记住...
When great deeds are remembered in this jungle...
有一个名字高高在上
one name will stand above all others--
我们的朋友, 布鲁, 一只伟大的熊.
our friend, Baloo, the bear.
他真煽情 - 布鲁给我们的记忆...
He's crackin' me up  - The memory of Baloo's...
它的勇敢和牺牲...
sacrifice and bravey...
将永远铭刻在我们的心上.
will forever be engraved on our saddened hearts.
太棒了 - 布鲁倒下的地方--
Beautiful - This spot where Baloo fell...
将成为丛林里的圣地...
will always be a hallowed place in the jungle...
因为这里躺着自然界--
for there lies one of nature's...
最高尚的动物
noblest creatures.
我希望我妈妈能听到这些
I wish my mother could've heard this.
现在我们得走了
It's best we leave now.
过来，人兽
Come along, man cub.
嘿，别就不说了，巴吉拉 你说得太感人了！
Hey, don't stop now, Baghee. You're doin' great!
再说一些，继续说吧
There's more, lots more.
什么, 你这个大骗子!
Why, you big fraud!
你 你 你这个装模做样的家伙!
You, you, you four-flusher!
我-我受够了--我--
I-I'm fed up, and I-I--
布鲁！你没事！
Baloo! You're all right!
谁，我吗？我当然没事
Who, me? Sure I am.
感觉不能再好了
Never felt better.
你的确让我们担心
You sure had us worried.
哦，我只是休息了一下
Ah, I was just takin' five.
你知道吗, 刚才很过瘾.
You know, playin' it cool.
是的，那老虎不堪一击
Yeah, but he was too easy.
你真好，熊爸爸
Good old Papa Bear.
没有这个小家伙，有些无趣，是不是?
It's going to be a bit dull without the little bloke, isn't it?
耶。那么我们干什么呢？
Yeah. So what we gonna do?
不知道 嘿，别又来了
I don't know. Hey, now, don't start that again!
嘿，巴吉拉， 你错过这次行动真太惨了
Hey, Baghee, too bad you missed the action.
你要是看见我把那该死的老虎打得落花流水就好了
You should have seen how I made a sucker out of old Stripes with that left up in his face.
隆，隆 我就是这样揍他
Boom, boom, I was givin' him. Whang!
你知道吗？我们是一对好伙伴
You wanna know somethin'? We're good sparrin' partners.
你最好知道这一点
You'd better believe it.
是，先生
Yes, sir.
没有什么能够分开我们.
Nothin' or nobody is ever gonna come between us again.
我的家园
My own home
看，那是什么？ - 噢，是人类村庄
Look. What's that? - Oh, it's the man village.
不，不，我指的那个
No, no. I mean that.
忘记那些，他们只会给你带来麻烦.
Forget about those. They ain't nothin' but trouble.
等一下 我以前从来没有见过
Just a minute. I've never seen one before.
现在你看到了，我们走吧
So you've seen one. So let's go.
我很快就回来，让我好好看看.
I'll be right back.I want a better look.
毛戈力，等一下 - 噢，布鲁
Mowgli, wait a minute - Ah, Baloo.
就让他好好看一下
Let him have a better look.
爸爸在林中打猎
Father's hunting in the forest
妈妈在家中做饭
Mother's cooking in the home
我要去打水
I must go to fetch the water
直到有一天我长大成人
Till the day that I am grown
直到我长大成人
Till I'm grown
我要去打水
I must go to fetch the water
直到我长大成人
Till the day that I am grown
那时我会有个英俊的丈夫
Then I will have a handsome husband
和一个我自己的女儿
And a daughter of my own
我会让她来打水
And I'll send her to fetch the water
我就在家中做饭
I'll be cooking in the home
那时我派她去打水
Then I'll send her to fetch the water
我就在家中做饭
I'll be cooking in my home
她故意那样做的
She did that on purpose.
很显然是
Obviously.
毛戈力，回来，回来！
Mowgli, come back. Come back!
继续走！继续走！
Go on! Go on!
他被迷住了
He's hooked.
哦，这是必然的，布鲁
Ah, it was inevitable, Baloo.
这孩子已经无法自拔，这是命中注定的
The boy couldn't help himself. It was bound to happen.
毛戈力到了他该去的地方了
Mowgli is where he belongs now.
耶--
Yeah...
我想你是对的
I guess you're right.
但我仍然认为他可以做一只大熊
But I still think he'd have made one swell bear.
好吧，巴吉老伙计
Well, come on, Baghee buddy.
让我们回到属于我们的地方...
Let's get back to where we belong...
跟着节拍...
and get with the beat.
寻找必需品
Look for the bare necessities
最基本的必需品
The simple bare necessities
忘却你的忧虑和矛盾
Forget about your worries And your strife
我的意思是最基本的必需品
I mean the bare necessities
是自然的力量
Are Mother Nature's recipes
将带来生活最起码的必需品
That bring the bare necessities of life